# HELLO,

I saw your job posting on Stack Overflow and I wanted to offer myself as a potential candidate for the position of Full Stack JavaScript Developer.

I don't have a CS degree. I started out as a designer and got into programming to take control of design implementation, because I cared. I discovered an entire universe to explore through web servers and I haven't looked back.

I also love the stack. The command line is an adventure and nix is my crush. Above all, I love uptime; cloud services that can deliver my content while not making kittens cry are my buddies.

I have a laundry list of skills and hefty experience to offer A Different Engine:

- \* More than 10 years designing and programming mobile and desktop compatible websites using multiple front-end and server-side web publishing languages: NodeJS, Wordpress, ActionScript, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, MySQL, PERL, JSON, XML Technologies and HTML 5.
- \* Deep understanding of legacy and modern browsers capabilities and developing appropriate fallbacks when necessary.
- Strong CSS knowledge with or without compilers.
- Understanding the reasons for CSS sprites and data-uri's.
- HTML 5 Canvas game development and code optimization: logic, speed, buffering and object management.
- Deep experience in Backbone.js, Node.js, Express.js.
- \* Daily usage of responsive and server-side techniques to deliver appropriately formatted content to end-user's browser and device types.
- \* Strong LAMP and Nginx stack experience coupled with Amazon Web Services: SES, SNS, Route 53, EC2, OpWorks, Dynamo DB, RDS, LAMBDA and Elastic Beanstalk.
- \* Expert usage of GIT/Bitbucket for automated deployments.
- \* Strong SSH and Linux command line skills.
- \* Great understanding of Apache and Nginx configuration for general setups and proxies.
- \* Strong email experience using Amazon SES and the DKIM setups required for reverse DNS.
- \* Server-side automation to consume content from Twitter, Google Maps, Instagram and other 3rd party XML/JSON feeds.
- \* Usage of the LESS framework to speed up CSS production.
- \* MySQL database setup, grants and maintenance.
- \* Profound understanding of Objective C development, certificate integration, Post Notifications and good fundamental knowledge of Android SDK.

Take a look at my work and qualifications; I would love to talk.

SINCERELY, ANTHONY BAKER portfolio.deluxeluxury.com

# **ANTHONY BAKER**

# WORK EXPERIENCE

THE MORRISON AGENCY ATLANTA, GA

Senior Web Developer 2015 to Present

U1 DESIGN/HOTHOUSE INC. ATLANTA, GA

Senior Designer/Developer 2005 to 2015

DELUXE LUXURY DESIGN MONTREAL, QC

Freelancer 2001 to 2005

MYBUTLER.COM MONTREAL, QC

Senior Designer 1998 to 2001

STILL CURRENT DESIGN ATLANTA. GA

Designer 1991 to 1998

# EXPERIENCED IN THE FOLLOWING TASKS AND PROJECT TYPES:

Art Direction

Team Supervision

Web Design

Front End and Back End Development

HTML5 Applications

Rich Media Banners and Microsites

Responsive Web Development

Facebook Applications

User Interface Development

E-commerce Design

Database and System Administration

External Agency Management

Identity and Campaign Development

Branding and Style Guides

**New Business Presentations** 

Project Estimation

Print Design, Production and Supervision

Tradeshow Design and Management

#### **GITHUB PROFILE:**

github.com/SuperFastCola

#### **PORTFOLIO:**

portfolio.deluxeluxury.com

# SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

#### **ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE 5**

Edge Animator, Illustrator, Photoshop Extended, InDesign, Flash, Dreamweaver, After Effects and SoundBooth

#### **MICROSOFT OFFICE**

Word, Powerpoint and Excel

## PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

Appcelerator, NodeJS, HTML 4 & 5, CSS 2, CSS 3, LESS/SASS, Backbone.js, Underscore.js Facebook API, Instagram API, Twitter API, Google Maps API, JQuery, Javascript, PHP 4 & 5, MySQL, GIT, Actionscript 2 & 3, XML, XSD, DTD, Regular Expressions, AJAX Patterns, Chef, Wordpress 3, Perl and Linux Administration.

Familiarity: AngularJS, MongoDB, ThreeJS, Objective-C.

### **DEPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE**

Amazon Web Services (Lambda, SES, SNS, S3, EC2, Route 53, Elastic Beanstalk, Dynamo DB, OpWorks and RDS)

# **RECOGNITION**

#### **CTAM MARK AWARDS 2012**

Gold - Your Summer Solution

Silver - Celebrate A Hallmark Year 2011

Silver - E! Red Carpet Affiliate Promotion

#### CTAM MARK AWARDS 2011

Gold - Bravo The Fashion Show Promotion

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

**UNIVERSITY OF MONTREAL** 

2003 TO 2004

Internet Programming

ART INSTITUTE OF ATLANTA

1989 TO 1991

Associates in Visual Communications

# ANTHONY BAKER

# **CODE SAMPLES**

#### SES, SNS, DynamoDB and Google Maps service integration with AWS Lambda and Node.js

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/nodeplay

#### **Automated Deployment Handler for BitBucket Integration**

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/autodeploy/blob/master/DeployHandler.php

#### **Essential sound-mixing board code for Teen Beach Beats:**

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/MusicManager/blob/master/MusicManager.js

#### Email sending class in PHP with outbound to Amazon SES:

Incorporates another custom class to open HTML files and replace selected tags with appropriate data and tracking elements.

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/email-sender-amazon/blob/master/MailSimple.php

#### TimeZone Detection

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/timezonehandler

#### **NodeJS sweepstakes application:**

Form field validation, HTML parsing and tag replacement, multi-lingual, data pushed to AWS Dynamo DB. https://github.com/SuperFastCola/node-site/blob/master/app.js

#### Javascript video detection class with legacy (IE8) fallback to Vimeo:

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/video/blob/master/video.js

#### **Brief implementation of video class:**

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/video

#### **General browser detection class:**

Gets a general feel of browser, device types and provides touch/click detection.

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/Browser.js/blob/master/browser.js

#### **HTML5 Game development:**

Canvas-based, request animation frame, Javascript object memory management and off-screen frame buffer. https://github.com/SuperFastCola/Ball-Thrower-Game-Code/blob/master/ballthrower.js

## Javascript and HTML5 canvas greeting card creation:

General canvas-based image manipulation (rotation, scale and montage).

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/camera\_capture\_manipulate\_as3\_javascript/blob/master/javascript/abcphotoapp.js

#### Facebook image upload and cropping/resizing mechanism:

Facebook permission-based account access, uses GD Library for processing and manipulation.

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/facebook\_processing\_ajax/blob/master/fb\_ajax.php

# **Portfolio Site:**

Responsive image sourcing with viewing area entry loading. BackboneJS, Underscore, LESS.

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/dld\_site/blob/master/javascript/new\_dld\_v1.js

#### My personal LESS bootstrap:

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/dld\_site/blob/master/css/new\_dld\_v1.less

#### **Wordpress integration:**

Template customization with additional short-tag/options processing.

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/wordpress\_theme\_customization/blob/master/functions.php

https://github.com/SuperFastCola/wordpress\_theme\_customization/blob/master/index.php

# ANTHONY BAKER

## SELECTED CODING PROJECTS

#### **CNNE VIDEO ON DEMAND SWEEPSTAKES**

Sweepstakes entry site in NodeJS. http://cnnevod.deluxeluxury.com

#### **Responsibilities:**

Full front and back-end.

Responsive integration.

Amazon Web Services setup:

Route53, EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, Dynamo DB, S3.

NGINX, NodeJS, PHPFPM setup and testing on staging servers.

Auto-deployment for staging versions from Bitbucket repositories.

#### Challenges:

HTML file parsing and tag replacement for tracking. Safari caching issues.

Forever installation and run-levels configuration.

#### **FYI NETWORK**

Create your own Facebook cover image. http://yourhyphenatedlife.com/?no\_redirect

#### **Responsibilities:**

Full front and back-end.

Facebook account photo permissions process Integration.

Alternate file upload version.

SSL installation and integration.

Amazon Web Services setup:

Route53, EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, S3.

Auto-deployment for staging versions from Bitbucket repositories.

CSS3 transitions, animation fall-backs and site redirection (to site not in Facebook Page tab) for IE8 and mobile users.

## Challenges:

Creating custom cropping functionality using GD library.

Debug of permissions issues on front and back-end.

Parsing Facebook photo data to get most liked and commented photo imagery.

Auto-pushing imagery to AWS S3.

#### PLAY THE BOARDWALK:

Mobile and desktop (IE9 minimum) compatible sweepstakes entry with gaming component. https://hothousesecure.com/playtheboardwalk/

#### Responsibilities:

Game development.

Front-end development.

Technical and design requirements

Game development research - (looked into a few engines and decided I had to do custom work)

#### **Challenges:**

Hit detection.

Rotation calculation.

Sprite loading.

Javascript object memory management.

Mouse coordinates calculations for minimized and maximized window; each browser has slightly different calculations.

Mobile device testing and debug.

#### **TEEN BEACH BEATS**

Social Sound Mixing Board. http://teenbeach2.deluxeluxury.com

#### **Responsibilities:**

UX design.

Full front and back-end development.

Responsive web development.

Mixing board development.

#### **Challenges:**

Using 3rd party howler framework to create mobile and IE9 compatible mixing experience.

Delivering a seamlessly looping background track.

Crab animation sychronization with tempo.

Social media sharing with dynamically generated urls.